Finding Aid for the Francis Craig Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Francis Craig Collection
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0091
2.51 linear feet
Biographical Note
Francis Jackson Craig was born in Dickson, Tennessee, on September 10, 1900, the ninth of ten children of a Methodist minister. Craig entered Vanderbilt University in January 1919 after a brief stint in the Army between his eighteenth birthday and the signing of the armistice that ended World War I. A talented pianist, he formed a dance band in 1920 to help pay his college expenses. After graduating in 1922, he continued his music career. On October 20, 1924, he married Elizabeth Gewin, whom he met while performing in Birmingham, Alabama.
For the first few years, his band kept busy playing dances, parties, and proms. In 1924, they received a two-week engagement to play at the Hermitage Hotel in downtown Nashville. That “two-week” engagement lasted until 1946. From 1925 to 1947, the band’s performances were broadcast live over WSM radio in Nashville and were carried on national network radio. They also toured extensively during that period and made numerous recordings. Craig and his band recorded at various times on the Columbia, MGM, Bullet, and Decca labels. Nationally recognized entertainers who got their start with Francis Craig included James Melton, Snooky Lanson, Kenny Sargent, Phil Harris, and Dinah Shore.
In 1946, Craig decided to give up performing and took a position as a disc jockey at WSM. His farewell recording, however, became a hit and led to two more years of touring and personal appearances. “Near You” on the Bullet label, became the first recording done in Nashville to sell over a million copies; it eventually sold in excess of two and a half million. In addition, seventeen other companies recorded the song. The next year Craig’s “Beg Your Pardon” also became a hit and went on to sell more than a million copies. Craig is also famous for Vanderbilt’s Dynamite song. After touring in 1947 and 1948, Craig returned to Nashville to work for the radio station. He died on November 20, 1966.
Scope and Content Note
The Francis Craig Collection contains material ranging in date from 1919 to 1990 and make up 1.88 linear feet. The papers include personal and biographical information, correspondence, memorabilia, and photographs. The major portion of the collection, however, dates from the 1930’s and 1940’s and consists of clippings, sheet music, and recordings. The papers are arranged in five series:
General File
Newspaper Clippings and Publications
Sheet Music
Photographs
Recordings
- File Listing
  - Series I. General
    - Correspondence – Outgoing – 2 letters, April 28, 1944; Sept. 19, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Incoming – Barton, Margaret – Craig, Robert J. (father) (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence – Incoming – Crooker, Herbert – Tanberg, Frances Hill (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence – Donia Craig Dickerson, outgoing Sept. 24, 1988; and incoming from Pee Wee Marquette, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Personal and Biographical – items from, 1919, 1937, 1948, 1951, 1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Personal and Biographical – Memorabilia, 1941 – 42, 1948, 1951, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Publicity Flyers, c., 1947 – 48 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hermitage Hotel – Donation of Memorabilia, 1981, includes correspondence, invitations, menus, guest lists (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lawsuit, 1953, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit, Thelma Hester Jones, Appellant vs. Francis Craig, Appellee (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Radio Scripts, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Seventh Infantry Bayonet Division, 1960; History, letter, and words to the song “Arirang” (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Series II. Newspaper Clippings and Publications
    - About Francis Craig, [1930], 1937, 1945 – 48, 1952, 1955, 1961, 1965, 1977, 1986, 1990, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      [1930] Re: stay in Rockies for health ( 2 items)
      February 7, 1937 – “Music Master is Maker of Magic,” Birmingham News-Age-Herald (2 copies)
      April 20, 1937 – “Nick Kenny Speaking.. .” Daily Mirro r (place unknown)
      May 23, 1937 – “Francis Craig Piping Majors Up from Dixie,” New York Enquirer
      June 7, 1945 – “Nashville Profile” [of Craig] by Mary Jane Brooks, Nashville Banner
      March 7, 1946 – “Francis Craig to Play Dance Here April 4,” Union City Daily [Advance?]
      June 15, 1946 – “Craig Band Broadcasts From Here,” The Cherry Point Wind Sock [NC]
      1947 – “Near You’s Author Tells How It’s Done,” by Lib Wiley, Lynchburg, Virginia [paper unknown]
      September 11, 1947 – “Newsweek Honors Craig” Nashville Banner
      October 17, 1947 – “Screen Reviews” by Prunella Hall, Boston Post
      October 19, 1947 – “Corny Arrangement Leads Musician to Jackpot with Top Platter Seller,” Mobile Press Register
      October 24, 1947 – “State Presents Francis Craig” Hartford Times
      October 29, 1947 – “ Top O’ the Morning” Nashville Tennessean
      December 20, 1947 – “Vaudeville Reviews – Loew’s State, NY” Variety
      March 4, 1948 – “In this Corner,” by Cedric Adams, Minneapolis Star
      April 24, 1948 – “Box Office Barometer,” Billboard Personal Appearances Supplement
      May 3, 1948 – “In this Corner,” by Cedric Adams, Minneapolis Star
      May 26, 1948 – “Francis Craig Impresses Folk Here as Southern Gentleman,” Paducah Sun Democrat (2 copies )
      March 23, 1952 – “Francis Craig to be Honored.. .” by Frank Sartwell, Jr. Washington Sunday Star
      August 27, 1955 – “ I Remember.. .” Nashville Banner ( 3 copies)
      July 2, 1961 – “Now and Then with Nashville Music Men,” by Pat Anderson, Nashville Tennessean
      February 16, 1967 – “Big-Time Composer Visiting in Naples,” [Naples, Florida] Collier County News
      March 20, 1977 – “ ‘Near You’ Still on Top After All These Years,” by Laura Eipper, Nashville Tennessean (9 copies)
      [1986?] – “’Near You’ was Craig’s Lucky Accident,” Nashville Banner (3 originals and 4 photocopies)
      August 20, 1990 – “Tennessee’s Musical Influence Great,” by Belden Menkus, Nashvile Tennessean
    - About Francis Craig, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Subject Files – Advertisements, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Subject Files – Hermitage Hotel, 1981, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Subject Files – People – Bulleit, Jim, 1948, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Subject Files – People – DeLuca, Gaetano, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Subject Files – People – Hall, Jim, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Subject Files – People – Kerr, Anita, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Subject Files – People – Lamm, Robert, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Subject Files – People – Lansom, Snooky, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Subject Files – People – Lenk, Walter Albert, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Subject Files – People – Marquette, Pee Wee, 1978, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Subject Files – People – McEwen, Red, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Subject Files – People – Melton, James, 1961, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Subject Files – Songs – “Beg Your Pardon”, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Subject Files – Songs – “Near You”, 1947 – 48, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Subject Files – Songs – other, 1979, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Subject Files – Vanderbilt University, 1933, 1946, 1948, 1967, other (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Series II. Newspaper Clippings and Publications
    - Subject Files – The Billboard, Jan. 3, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Subject Files – Juke Box Record Review, September 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Subject Files – “Opryland: A Modern Musical Adventure,”, April 15, 1972 in Billboard (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Subject Files – WSM (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Subject Files – Photographs and photo spreads (no articles), 1938, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbooks – photocopies – (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbooks – photocopies – (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbooks – photocopies – (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Series III. Sheet Music
    - “Beg Your Pardon” (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - “ A Broken Heart Must Cry”, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - “Do Me a Favor, Will Ya?”, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - “Fly Our Flag Forever”, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - “Fly Our Flag Forever” (addition 3/11/08) with accompanying materials (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - “Foolin’”, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “I Thought I was Dreaming”, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Lost Motion”, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - “Near You”, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - “Near You” foreign and other versions (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - “Put All Your Love in a Cookie Jar,”, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - “Red Rose,”, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - “She’s a Bad Little Girl,”, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - “Sometimes I Wonder,”, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - “When Vandy Starts to Fight”, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - “Won’t You Buy Some Girl Scout Cookies” 1957 [Manuscript] (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Orchestrations “Lost Motion” (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Orchestrations “The Nashville Banner March” (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Series III. Sheet Music
    - Orchestrations “Red Rose” (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Orchestrations “When Vandy Starts to Fight” (the Dynamite Song) [w/manuscript] (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Other composers (featuring Francis Craig), 1926, 1930, 1936-38, 1940-41 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      “Boo Hoo,” 1937
      “Day Dreaming,” 1941
      “Dear Diary,” 1936
      “Don’t Take the Sweet Out of Sweetheart,” 1936
      “Hula Blues,” 1939
      “I Hear Bluebirds,”1940
      “I Still Get A Thrill,” 1930
      “In the Chapel in the Moonlight,” 1936
      “Let Me Dream of Havana,” 1935
      “The Little Old-Fashioned Music Box,” 1924
    - Other composers (featuring Francis Craig), 1926, 1930, 1936 -38, 1940-41 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      “Moon Over Burma” 1940
      “On a Little Dream Ranch,” 1937
      “Polka Dots and Moonbeams,” 1940
      “Shame on You,” 1937
      “Something Seems to Tell Me,” [date ?] – fragment
      “Sweetheart Let’s Grow Old Together”
      “Taint Good,” 1936
      “Talking to the Moon,” 1926
      “There’s a Far-Away Look in Your Eye,” 1938
  - Series IV. Photographs
    - Francis Craig, 1931; 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Francis Craig, n.d.; 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Billboard, n.d..; 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Billy Schaeffer and Cecil Bailey, 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Burns Birds” Bill Burns, n.d.; 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Burns Birds” and Irene Burns, 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - FC w/ Cosmopolitan Hotel Personnel, 1932; 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Dancers –Unidentified, n.d.; 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - “Flying to Cherry Point, NC”, 1946; 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Freddy Martin and Francis Craig, 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - FC w/ his mascot “Pee Wee”, 1932; 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - James Barton, n.d.; [1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Jerry Murad’s Harmonicats, 1948; 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Jim Lownsbury and Francis Craig, 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Lander and Holland, Dec. 7, 1947; 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Marjorie and James Melton’s Wedding, 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. Lupton, “This is Your Life” Clarksville, Tennessee, Fall, 1953; 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Photograph postcards – FC –blank, n.d.; 6 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Photograph postcards – orchestra, 1949 (to Mrs. Buford Dickerson); 1 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ray Thortun and Francis Craig, 1 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Ray Brown and Francis Craig, September, 1955; 1 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Tex Beneke and Francis Craig, 1948; 1 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Tours, n.d.; 4 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Vaudeville, Loew’s State Marquee
      Billboard, location unknown
      Window display, location unknown
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Washington, D.C. Tour, 1948; 7 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - w/Bob and Florence Lamm, 1 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - w/Group, n.d.; 1 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Florence and Bob Lamm
      Jean Brown
      Ray Brown
      Pat Tiffault
      Fergee
      Junie Ferguson
    - w/Olee Elrick and Jack Owens, 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - w/Orchestra, n.d.; 3 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - w/Orchestra and Dancers, 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - w/Orin Remsnyder and Marion Woodward, 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Christmas Booth
      Gift for disabled veterans
    - w/Others at the piano, n.d.; 3 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - w/Unidentified Group, n.d.; 3 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - w/Unidentified Man, n.d.; 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - w/Unidentified Woman, n.d.; 2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Negatives, n.d.; 2 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      w/Snooky Lansom on Trumpet in VU Gym
      w/Dinah Shore
- Series V. Recordings
  - Audio Cassettes
    - 1. Cassette 1 side A disc transfers (Box 4)
      “The Sheik of Araby” “Way Down Upon the Swanee River” Donia Craig and Mary Baldwin – acetate disc
      “Ain’t She Sweet/Five Foot Two” “The World is Waiting for a Sunrise” unlabeled acetate disc
      “Frankie and Johnny” “Down Yonder” Baldwin Bom Shells – acetate disc
      “St. Louis Blues”Baldwin Bom Shells – acetate disc
      “Blue Moon Medley” Baldwin Bom Shells – acetate disc
      “One For My Baby” Piano and vocal Donia Craig – acetate disc
      “Ain’t She Sweet” “New Orleans” Baldwin Bom Shells – acetate disc
      “Waiting for the Robert E. Lee” “When The Saints Go Marching In” Baldwin Bom Shells –acetate disc
      Famous Vanderbilt Songs – The Alma Mater, Dynamite, Cheer for the Gold and Black Collegiate Recording Company VU 1001 – vinyl disc
  - Cassette 1 side B disc transfers
    “O’Alma Mater” sung by the Vanderbilt A Capella Choir Cyrus Daniel – Director Soloists: Jack Irvin a ’50 baritone and Virginia Osborn a ’49 soprano Collegiate Recording Company and VU 1002
    “I Thought I was Dreaming” Francis Craig and his Orchestra MGM 10378 – A
    “Tennessee Tango” Francis Craig and His Orchestra MGM 10378- B
    Red Carino interview by Jack Ridder WENT in Gloversville, New York – Sept. 11, 1947. Red is in Francis Craig’s Orchestra—discusses Bob Lamm, “Near You”
    “The Nashville Banner March” written by Francis Craig to commemorate The Banner’s 75th Anniversary April 190, 1951 – performed by the United States Navy Band conducted by LCdr. Charles Brendler, vinyl disc pressing
    “The Nashville Banner March” performed by Francis Craig and his Orchestra-Don Estes and the Anita Kerr Singers-vocalists vinyl disc pressing
    “The Nashville Banner March” performed by Francis Craig on piano vinyl disc pressing
    “Near You” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Decca 28089
  - Cassette 2 side A disc transfers
    “Stars and Stripes Medley” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Decca 28089
    “I’m Looking for a Sweetheart” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Bullet 1012A
    “Beg Your Pardon” Francis Craig and His Orchestra Bullet 1012B
    “Foolin” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Bullet 1013A
    “Do Me a Favor (Will Ya?)” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Bullet 1013B
    “I Still Get a Thrill” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Bullet 1040A
    “Disillusioned” Francis Craig and his Orchestra Bullet 1040B
    “Some Hearts Sing” Dick James – vocal, with the George Mitchell Choir and Ronnie Milne and his Orchestra London 544A
    “I Thought I was Dreaming” Dick James – vocal, with the George Mitchell Choir Don Lorusso-Hamond organ and guitar and bass accompaniment, written by (Carlson, Craig, Nolan) London 544B
    “Put All Your Love in a Cookie Jar” George Morgan (written by Morgan- Craig) Columbia 20594
    “Room Full of Roses” George Morgan Columbia 20594
  - Cassette 2 side B disc transfers
    salute to “Near You” radio broadcast – Hawaiian version – comedy
    orchestral version-comedy intro of Francis Craig- reading of resolution from city of Nashville by Mayor Tom Cummings – incomplete
    short broadcast from Meet Your Music Makers announcing Francis Craig to be on show soon
    Ira Cook and Meet Your Music Makers –interview Francis Craig 1-29-48
    more of interview – discusses “Near You” and “Beg Your Pardon” family life –(some speed problems starting here)
  - Cassette 3 side A disc transfers
    “Overture/Crazy Mani” Donia Craig VU 100
    “Let’s Have a Love Affair” by Jim Warwick and Becky Howell and Chorus “Unconventional Me” by Sanders Marshall VU 101
    “Fantasie De Parisienne” (Part 1) by Jack Irvin and Chorus VU 102
    “Fantasie De Parisienne” (Part 2) by Jack Irvin and Chorus VU 104
    “My Tomorrow” by Jack Irvin, Betsy Conway and Chorus VU 103
    “Where is My Heart” Jack Irvin “Matador” Walter Courtney VU 105 incomplete
  - Cassette 3 side B disc transfers
    “Where is My Heart” “Matador” continued from side A
    “My Heart Has Wings” by Jack Irvin and Chorus VU 106
    “Waxing Mellow Tonight” by Becky Howell and Chorus/ “In the Sun Again” by Becky Conway VU 107
    “In the Shade of the Moonlight” Francis Craig – Francis Craig at the Piano Dot 45 – 15400
    “If You Cared at All” Francis Craig – Francis Craig at the Piano Dot 45 – 15400
    - 2. Cassette 4 side A disc transfers (Box 4)
      1 Matinee Time – Jo Sherman interviews Francis Craig 3-20-62 WSM radio
      Discusses past band members and vocalists, playing ‘bones’ on Red Foley record, “Near You”, sales figures, Vanderbilt fight song (Dynamite), family history, “Beg Your Pardon” career highlights, James Melton, and “I Dreamt I Dwelt in Marble Halls” “Trip Around the World”
  - Cassette 4 side B disc transfers
    People in the Headlines – radio interview with Francis Craig, 12-2-40 part 1
    Interview with Francis Craig part 2 (listed as part 3)
    “Dynamite- When Vandy Starts to Fight” radio broadcast
    “The Hills of Tennessee” Roy Acuff from the Prince Albert Grand Ole Opry, 2-26-44
    The Choral Society and Marching Band perform Francis Craig’s “Red Rose” 9-19-47
    “Near You” side 2 of disc above – no label – New York NBC network radio broadcast
    Presentation of scroll to Francis Craig by Nashville Mayor Tom Cummings
    Salute to “Near You” comedy version of song by Wally Fowler and the Oak Ridge Quartet – radio broadcast 10-3-47
  - Cassette 5 side A tape transfers
    Craig family personal tape beginning August 19, 1954 – Thanksgiving – Sewing Club, birthdays – includes comments from Pee Wee Marquette – famous doorman of Byrdland club in New York City and alumni of the Craig band.
    - 3. Recordings – Tapes (7 ½ ips, reel to reel ) (Box 4)
      Peewee, Bill O and Teck, Francis and Bohham, Blue Heaven, Julie Webber, Gordon, Marion Overby, Birthday Dec. 29, 1956
      Matinee Time, Jo Sherman and Francis Craig, March 20, 1962
    - 4. (Box 4)
      Francis Craig, Studio Salute to “Near You” (October 3, 1947); interview with Francis Craig/Ira Cook (January 29, 1948); Meet Your Music Makers, nd; interview, Part 1, Francis Craig (December 2, 1940)
      Interview Part 3 (December 2, 1940); “When Vandy Starts to Fight,” nd; Roy Acuff/Prince Albert, “Hills of Tennessee” (December 26, 1944); “Red Rose” (September 19, 1947); presentation of scroll to Craig by Mayor Cummings, nd; salute to “Near You,” nd
- Series V – Recordings- Records
  - “Do Me A Favor (Will Ya?)/ “Foolin” (2 records) Francis Craig and His Orchestra, Francis Craig at the piano (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - “I Still Get a Thrill”/ “Disillusioned” (2 records ) Francis Craig and His Orchestra, Francis Craig at the piano (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - “I’m Looking for a Sweetheart”/ “Beg Your Pardon” Francis Craig and His Orchestra, Francis Craig at the Piano (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - “In the Shade of the Moonlight”/ “If You Care at All”45 rpm – Francis Craig (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “ The Nashville Banner March” Francis Craig, piano/ “To Commemorate the Banners’s “The Nashville Banner March” Francis Craig and Orchestra, 75th Anniversary April 10, 1951 w/Don Estes/The Anita Kerr Singersl (3 records) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - “ The Nashville Banner March” Francis Craig, piano/ “To Commemorate the Banners’s “The Nashville Banner March” Francis Craig and Orchestra, 75th Anniversary April 10, 1951 w/Don Estes/The Anita Kerr Singers (2 records) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - “The Nashville Banner March” words and music by Francis Craig in commemoration of the Nashville Banner’s 75 anniversary (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “The Nashville Banner March” played by the United States Navy Band conducted by LCDR. Charles Brendler (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - “The Nashville Banner March” played by Paul Lavalle and the Cities Service Band of America (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - “Near You”/ “Red Rose” Francis Craig and His Orchestra (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - “Near You”/ “Beg Your Pardon” Francis Craig 45rpm (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - “Near You”/ “Stars and Stripes Medley” Francis Craig and His Orchestra (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - “Tennessee Tango” Craig/Smith / “I Thought I was Dreaming” Craig/Carlson/Nolan (2 records) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Sheik” vocals by Donia Craig and Mary Baldwin 78rpm (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - “One for My Baby” piano and vocal Donia Craig/ “Blue Moon Medley,” Baldwin Bom Shells (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - “St. Louis Blues”/ “Frankie and Johnny”/ “Down Yonder” played by Baldwin Bom Shells (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - “Robert E. Lee”and “The Saints”/ “Ain’t She Sweet” and “New Orleans” by the Baldwin Bom Shells (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Scampers of 1953 Presents “The Fink in Paris” music and lyrics by John Jennings (4 singles, this is 1 of 4) VU100 Overture “Crazy Man!” Sung by Donia Craig/ VU 101 “Let’s Have a Love Affair”/ “Unconventional Me” 45rpm (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Scampers of 1953 presents “The Fink in Paris” music and lyrics by John Jennings (4 singles, this is 2 of 4) VU 102 Fantasie de Parisienne (Part 1); VU 104 Fantasie de Parisienne (part 2) 45rpm (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Scampers of 1953 presents “The Fink in Paris” music and lyrics by John Jennings (4 singles, this is 3 of 4) VU 103 “My Tomorrow” VU 105 “Where is My Heart” 45rpm (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Scampers of 1953 presents “The Fink in Paris” music and lyrics by John Jennings (4 singles, this is 4 of 4) VU 106 “My Heart has Wings” VU 107 “Waxing Mellow Tonight” 45rpm (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - “O Alma Mater,” Vanderbilt Acapella Choir; “Famous Vanderbilt Songs,” Vanderbilt Men’s Glee Club, Cyrus Daniel, Director; Jack Irvin and Virginia Osborn soloists (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - “I Thought I Was Dreaming”/ “Some Hearts Sing” Dick James vocal, with the George Mitchell Choir and Don Lorusso (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - “Papa Celestin’s “Golden Wedding” LP Album that includes “Down by the Riverside” and “When the Saints go Marching in” (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - “Put All Your Love in a Cookie Jar”/ “Room Full of Roses” George Morgan, vocal with String Band Orchestra (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - “The United Press March” by Paul Lavalle.Played by the Band of America (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - “Transfusion, Nervous Norvus”/”Dig, Nervous Norvus” (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - “Sonata in G” by Robert Schumann, rec’d by Roger Griffith, May 1952, 3rd movement 2nd piano sonata, Burrill Phillips (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - “Red Carina – Jack Ridder interview “ aired on 1340 Club over WENT Gloversville, NY on, September 11, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified recording (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified recording (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified recording (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Oversize - Cardboard head of Francis Craig, color, approximately 17” x 27”